So from standing, fold to forward in Uttanasana and then step your right leg back behind you into Lunge Pose, take the right heel down to the floor and turn the right toes forty five degrees toward the right, then bend your left leg nice and deep and take your hands up to your front knee.
So now what we have to do is get the back leg to do what we call a big inner spiral, so that means the inner edge of the back leg needs to move back and widen toward the right in order to get our hips more in alignment.
So, bow forward and move both of your inner thighs back.
Do you see that?
Since you move your inner thighs back, then, draw the tail bone down, that's it, and then inhale and lift up.
Sweep the arms open to the sky and hold for a few more full breaths and surrender your front leg a little more deeply so the front leg is full and brave.
Exhale, fold forward, inhale step forward.
And let's do the second side together.
Step your left leg back.
Now you can line up the heels in line with each other, or if that feels like your hips are a little too tight to do that, it's fine to take the left leg a little more toward the left, so little wider stance will give you more freedom.
Then bend your front leg nice and deep, take your hands to your front knee, do big inner spiral in the back leg, so to do that bow forward and move your groins back, move your thighs back, and as they go back, you feel the whole left hip will spin around.
Then scoop the tail bone down, bend the right leg more deeply, as the right leg bends lift up through the spine and sweep your arms open to the sky.
And release fold forward, inhale step forward.
And then push in to your feet, take your hands to your hips, lift half way up, draw the shoulder blades into the back and lift with your heart to rise up standing.